CIO Files of John L. Lewis, Pt. II: CIO General Files on Microfilm 5831 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- AFL. 1935 -1945 (Reel 17)
  - AFL. 1943., 9 (Reel 17)
    170 pp.: AFL-UMWA negotiations on reaffiliation of UMWA; reaction of AFL unions to application for reaffiliation of UMWA; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; support for UMWA in captive mines dispute; war mobilization efforts; allegations of Communist Influence of CIO; digest of proceedings of 1943 AFL convention; news releases; National War Labor Board; IBT strikes; no-strike pledge; AFL state and local organizations; newsclippings; Daniel J. Tobin; John O'Leary; Thomas Kennedy; Percy Tetlow; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz; William Green; Matthew Woll; George Q. Lynch; George L. Berry; David Dubinsky; John Hawk; FDR; Victor A. Olander; William Davis; I.M. Ornburn.
  - AFL. [1943-]1944., 10 (Reel 17)
    98 pp.: Report of proceedings of 1944 AFL convention; AFL executive council failure to act on UMWA applications for reaffiliation and UMWA withdrawal of application; AFL-UMWA unity negotiations; AFL jurisdictional disputes with UMWA District 50; AFL executive council matters; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Daniel J. Tobin; George Meany; Matthew Woll; Harry C. Bates; A.D. Lewis; John Kmetz.
  - AFL. [1943-]1945., 1944-1945; 11 (Reel 17)
    97 pp.: AFL-UMWA controversy and unity negotiations; UMWA application for reaffiliation with AFL; report of proceedings of 1943 AFL convention; AFL executive council matters; war mobilization efforts; legislative programs; AFL jurisdictional disputes with UMWA District 50; Daniel J. Tobin; William Green; Matthew Woll; Boris Shishkin; John T. Mates; George Meany
- AFL. 1946 -1947 (Reel 18)
  - AFL--State Federations of Labor., 1946; 1 (Reel 18)
    97 pp.: State AFL organizations; AFL general and district presidents; AFL southern organizing campaign; Labor's Non-partisan League; congratulations on UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; George L. Googe; Joe Morris; David Fowler; John T. Jones.
  - AFL--General., 1946; 2 (Reel 18)
    265 pp.: Local AFL organizations; UMWA District 50; press relations; political activities; use of injunctions in labor disputes; UMWA contract negotiations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL executive council matters; AFL-CIO cooperative proposals; international labor relations; southern organizing campaigns; AFL-CIO competition; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Communist influence in the CIO; AFL general and district organizers; political activities; labor racketeering activities; health and welfare fund manipulations; Union Labor Life Insurance Company; legislative programs; UMWA public relations; UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; UMWA payment of per capita to AFL; John J. Mates; Matthew Woll; Harry S Truman; Drew Pearson; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Philip Murray; George L. Googe; George Meany; John T. Jones; A.D. Lewis; Cecil Owen; I.M. Ornburn; Roy M. Brewer; Ora E. Gasaway.
  - AFL--Convention., 1946; 3 (Reel 18)
    84 pp.: Minutes of meetings of AFL executive council during 1946 AFL convention; jurisdictional disputes; AFL state and local organizations; international labor relations; organizing drives; plans for 1946 AFL convention; WFTU; UMWA district presidents; UMWA reaffiliation with AFL; William Green; Jesse Clark; Ed J. Brown; J.J. Duffy; George Meany; H.W. Davis; W.D. Mahon; George M. Harrison; Matthew Woll; William C. Doherty; K.C. Adams.
  - AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council., 1946; 4 (Reel 18)
    January 21-31, 1946. 200 pp.: Acceptance of UMWA application for reaffiliation with AFL; election of John L. Lewis to the AFL executive council; UMWA-PMWA competition; AFL factionalism and internal politics; International Association of Machinists' refusal to pay per capita to the AFL; AFL state and local organizations; legislative programs; jurisdictional disputes; international labor relations; International Federation of Trade Unions (IFTU); AFL Metal Trades Department; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; postwar conversion plans; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; AFL-CIO competition; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; AFL general and district organizers; statistics regarding NLRB elections, 1941-1945; Olin Industries v. Joseph Barnett, et al. (US District Court for the Southern District of Illinois, opinion by Charles G. Briggle regarding reemployment of World War II veterans); William Green; Frank P. Fenton; John A. Owens; Walter Schevenels; William J. Kromelbein; Joseph N. Weber; A. Persion; William E. Maloney; Felix H. Knight; W.C. Birthright; William C. Doherty; Percy R. Bengough; George Meany.
  - AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council., 1946; 5 (Reel 18)
    May 15-22, 1946. 133 pp.: International Association of Machinists' refusal to pay per capita to the AFL; jurisdictional disputes; AFL state and local organizations; US Congress anti-labor legislation proposals; political activities; legislative programs; public relations activities; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; international labor relations; southern organizing campaign; withdrawal of PMWA from AFL; NLRB decisions; AFL-CIO competition in the canning industry; IBT; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; AFL general and district organizers; financial matters; AFL Metal Trades Department; AFL general and district organizers; financial matters; AFL Metal Trades Department; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; William Green; W.D. Mahon; George Meany; Harvey W. Brown; Woodruff Randolph; John Clinton; Earl Evans; Lester Washburn; Joseph D. Keenan; John P. Frey.
  - AFL--Minutes of Meetings of AFL Executive Council., 1946; 6 (Reel 18)
    August 12-20, 1946. 195 pp.: International labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Nebraska right-to-work state anti-labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Nebraska right-to-work state anti-labor legislation; International Association of Machinists' disassociation from AFL; ILO; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; jurisdictional disputes; IBT; National Farm Labor Union granted AFL affiliation; legislative programs; AFL-CIO competition; southern organizing campaign; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; AFL general and district organizers; AFL executive council report; farmers cooperative; retirement plans; organization of black workers@United Textile Workers of America; financial matters; membership of and payment per capita by AFL affiliates; William Green; W.D. Mahon; Percy R. Bengough; George W. Lawson; H.L. Mitchell; Matthew Woll; David Dubinsky; A.L. Spradling; James C. Petrillo; Daniel V. Flanagan; William L. Hutcheson; Walter Cenerazzo; Felix H. Knight; W.C. Birthright; William C. Doherty; George Meany; Daniel J. Tobin; William E. Maloney; James A. McConnell; George L. Googe.
  - AFL--State Federations of Labor., 1947; 7 (Reel 18)
    53 pp.: UMWA district presidents; 1947 West Virginia state AFL convention; AFL state and local organizations; Taft-Hartley Act; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Illinois state AFL publications; D.M. Stamper; Cecil J. Urbaniak; William Blizzard; George J. Titler; Ray Thomason; Joseph Angelo; Harry Bennett; R.O. Lewis; William Green; George Meany; Matthew Woll.
  - AFL-CIO Unity File., 1946; 8 (Reel 18)
    55 pp.: AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL executive council matters; CIO executive board matters; local union support for AFL-CIO unity; press relations; William Green; Philip Murray; George Meany; William L. Hutcheson; Daniel J. Tobin; Harry C. Bates.
  - AFL--Central Labor Unions., 1947; 9 (Reel 18)
    45 pp.: AFL state and local organizations; Taft-Hartley Act; political activities; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; legislative programs; William Green.
  - AFL--Central Labor Unions., 1946; 10 (Reel 18)
    16 pp.: AFL state and local organizations; southern organizing campaign; support for UMWA contract negotiations.
  - AFL--General., 1947; 11 (Reel 18)
    248 pp.: UMWA re-withdrawal from AFL; Havana Conference on Trade and Employment; international labor relations; National Farm Labor Union strike in Bakersfield, California; 1947 AFL convention; Taft-Hartley Act; UMWA district presidents; UMWA executive board; UMWA refusal to pay per capita to AFL; AFL executive council matters; negotiations with International Association of Machinists for reaffiliation with AFL; AFL housing committee; AFL state and local organizations; AFL general and district organizers; support for UMWA contract negotiations; legislative programs; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; jurisdictional disputes; UMWA District 50; AFL Building and Construction Trades Department; AFL-CIO competition; political activities; public relations efforts; ILO; UMWA loan to National Federation of Telephone Workers; US government legal case against UMWA; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; financial matters; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; Labor's Non-Partisan League; William L. Hutcheson; William Green; Lee W. Minton; Lewis C. Thorne; George Meany; Matthew Woll; Harvey W. Brown; Eric Peterson; John O'Leary; A.D. Lewis; Frank P. Fenton; Daniel J. Tobin; David Dubinsky; Richard F. Walsh; Daniel W. Tracy; George J. Titler; Richard J. Gray; Harry S Truman; Robert J. Watt; John Kmetz; Thomas Kennedy; Joseph Beirne; Joseph A. Padway; William C. Doherty; Philip Murray; John T. Jones; I.M. Ornburn; Irving Brown.
- AFL. 1947 -1955 (Reel 19)
  - AFL--Convention., 1947; 1 (Reel 19)
    October 1947. 69 pp.: Report of proceedings of 1947 convention; international labor relations; Taft- Hartley Act; AFL factionalism and internal politics; plans for 1947 AFL convention; William Green; Joseph P. Keenan; Thomas Kennedy; Daniel J. Tobin; George Meany; Lester Washburn; David Dubinsky; Harry S Truman.
  - AFL--Building., 1947; 2 (Reel 19)
    26 pp.: Plans for purchase of property in the District of Columbia; financial matters; AFL executive council matters; William Green; George Meany.
  - AFL--Executive Council Meetings., 1947; 3 (Reel 19)
    248 pp.: Minutes of meetings of the AFL executive council; postwar conversion; international labor relations; jurisdictional disputes; international Association of Machinists; Allied Printing Trades Council; legislative programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters; Hollywood, California, motion picture studios controversy; British Trades Union Congress; southern organizing campaign; US government legal case against UMWA; retirement annuity plan for AFL employees; anti-labor legislation; financial matters; AFL general and district organizers; membership of and payment of per capita by AFL affiliates; postwar economic conditions in Germany; plans for purchase of property in the District of Columbia; George Meany; Henry Rutz; William Green; George L. Berry; Edward J. Volz; Philip Murray; Joseph N. Weber; Robert Montgomery; Ed J. Brown; Thomas Kennedy; Matthew J. Burns; Richard F. Walsh; Hugo Ernst; William L. Hutcheson; William C. Doherty; Israel Feinberg; W.D. Mahon; W.C. Birthright; Felix H. Knight; Frank Duffy; William E. Maloney; John F. McNamara; Dean Acheson.
  - AFL. 1948., 4 (Reel 19)
    41 pp.: UMWA withdrawal from AFL; 1948 AFL convention; international labor relations; support for UMWA contract negotiations; AFL executive council matters; use of injunctions in labor disputes; AFL state and local organizations; AFL cooperation with UMWA in legal case before the US Supreme Court; AFL educational programs; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; William Green; Leon Blum; Matthew Woll.
  - AFL. 1949., 5 (Reel 19)
    34 pp.: Criticism of AFL presidency of William Green; proposed AFL strike fund assistance for United Steelworkers of America; support for labor unity negotiations; International Fishermen and Allied Workers of America; AFL and UMWA state and local organizations; William Green; J.F. Jurich; Philip Murray; George Griffiths; Thomas Kennedy; Florence Thorne; John J. Mates.
  - AFL. 1950., 6 (Reel 19)
    111 pp.: AFL educational programs; minutes of meetings of Workers Education Bureau of America; AFL absorption of Workers Education Bureau of America; ILGWU-UMWA cooperation; ILGWU strikes; UMWA district presidents; AFL and UMWA support for community chest campaigns; international labor relations; Economic Cooperation Administration; UMWA health and safety programs; labor-management cooperation; labor unity negotiations; economic conditions in Argentina; support for UMWA contract negotiations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; John D. Connors; Thomas Kennedy; Michael J. Kosik; Thomas M. Holleran; Reg Kennedy; Matthew Woll; William Green; Philip Murray; Philip Reed; Serafino Romualdi; A.J. Hayes.
  - AFL. 1950., 7 (Reel 19)
    24 pp.: 1950 AFL convention; UMWA District 50 competition with AFL; proposed AFL organization of coal miners; 1950 AFL Indiana state convention; UMWA district presidents; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL no-strike pledge; support for UMWA contract negotiations; Louis Austin; William Green; W.P. Kennedy; H.W. Fraser; Alvanley Johnston; A.J. Hayes; Philip Murray; John Owens.
  - AFL. 1951., 8 (Reel 19)
    65 pp.: AFL support for community chest campaigns@United Defense Fund support for USO clubs; legislative programs; political activities; the Smith Act (anti-labor legislation); international labor relations; AFL publications; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); AFL-CIO unity negotiations; William Green; Woodruff Randolph; Thomas Kennedy; Justin McCarthy; A. Philip Randolph; Reg Kennedy.
  - AFL. 1951., 9 (Reel 19)
    44 pp.: AFL-UMWA cooperation; US importation of natural gas from Canada; radio broadcasts; AFL publications; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); Taft-Hartley Act; AFL Construction and Building Trades Department; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; 1951 AFL convention; press relations; UMWA organization in Kentucky; William Green; Thomas Kennedy; Harry S Truman; Justin McCarthy; Richard J. Gray.
  - AFL. 1952., 10 (Reel 19)
    53 pp.: 1952 ACA convention; support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; support and criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; AFL press relations; investigation of the ILA on labor racketeering charges; international labor relations; 1952 AFL convention; Taft-Hartley Act; Labor's Non-Partisan League; international labor relations; AFL-UMWA cooperation; 1952 ILO conference; US importation of natural gas from Canada; Joseph P. Selly; Len De Caux; Thomas Kennedy; John J. Mates; William Green; John T. Jones; George P. Delaney; Paul K. Reed; John Owens.
  - AFL. 1952., 11 (Reel 19)
    70 pp.: National Committee for Labor Israel; AFL health and welfare programs; AFL health and welfare programs; AFL support for community chest programs; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; international labor relations; Taft-Hartley Act; legislative programs; political activities; AFL and CIO proposals before the 1952 Republican National Convention; UMWA mine safety legislative programs; UMWA District 50 jurisdictional dispute with International Typographical Union; George Meany; Thomas Kennedy; Mrs. William Green; Reg Kennedy; William Green; George P. Delaney; James B. Carey; Walter P. Reuther; John Owens; A.D. Lewis; Woodruff Randolph.
  - AFL. 1953., 12 (Reel 19)
    35 pp.: AFL-CIO negotiations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm)@United Brotherhood of Carpenters withdrawal from AFL; 1953 AFL convention; international labor relations; Moral Re-Armament Movement (MRA); UMWA District 50; UMWA-IBT cooperation; AFL-UMWA cooperation; AFL state and local organizations; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; ILGWU organizers; Thomas Kennedy; John Owens; M.A. Hutcheson; Dave Beck; William F. Schnitzler; Edward Kennedy; James L. McDevitt.
  - AFL. 1953., 13 (Reel 19)
    35 pp.: International Union of Operating Engineers labor racketeering; AFL Construction and Building Trades Department; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; AFL press relations; television broadcasts; Cecil Owen; George Meany.
  - AFL. 1954., 14 (Reel 19)
    47 pp.: Support for AFL-CIO unity negotiations; UAW factionalism and internal politics; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); conference of AFL and CIO maritime unions; Sailors' Union of the Pacific; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; international labor relations; Jules Kimmett; Justin McCarthy; John T. Jones; Matthew Woll.
  - AFL. 1954., 15 (Reel 19)
    114 pp.: ILA-IBT cooperation; NLRB decisions; AFL educational programs; criticism of Senator Joseph McCarthy; legislative programs; political activities; international labor relations; analysis of voting records of US congressmen; AFL support for community chest programs; UMWA pension fund applications; Moral Re-Armament Movement (MRA); UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; American Newspaper Guild strikes; CIO factionalism and internal politics; Taft-Hartley Act; CIO legislative programs; Dave Beck; James L. McDevitt; Thomas Kennedy; George Meany; Martin F. Durkin; Matthew Woll; David J. McDonald; Jacob F. Potofsky; Arthur J. Goldberg; Robert Oliver.
  - AFL. 1954-1955., 16 (Reel 19)
    [1954-]1955. 50 pp.: AFL-CIO no-raiding agreement; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; CIO publications; AFL-CIO constitution; 1955 AFL-CIO convention; AFL-CIO merger; international labor relations; AFL state and local organizations; Walter P. Reuther; George Meany; David Dubinsky; Anthony Wayne Smith; Richard H. Stroud; J. Scott Milne; Joseph D. Keenan; M.A. Hutcheson; George Duffy.
- AFL--Labor Unity, 1942-1956; United Steelworkers of America, 1949-1962 (Reel 20)
  - AFL--Labor Unity--AFL-CIO merger., 1955; 1 (Reel 20)
    December 1, 1955. 165 pp.: Television broadcasts; press relations; newsclippings; AFL-CIO unity negotiations; analysis of AFL-CIO membership, leadership, and organization power of affiliates; Transport Workers Union; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; AFL-CIO organizing campaigns; M.S. Rukeyser; James B. Carey; Justin McCarthy; Rex Lauck.
  - AFL--Labor Unity., 1955; 2 (Reel 20)
    41 pp.: Newsclippings regarding AFL-CIO merger.
  - AFL--Labor Unity--Regarding Matter of Loan to CIO from UMWA., 1942-1956; 3 (Reel 20)
    45 pp.: Newsclippings regarding AFL-CIO merger and UMWA demand for repayment of loans to CIO; UMWA demand for repayment of loans to CIO; UMWA non-payment of per capita tax prior to withdrawal from CIO; report on money owed to UMWA by CIO; statement of financial relationship of UMWA and CIO; James B. Carey; John Owens; Thomas Kennedy; J. Raymond Bell; Philip Murray; Kathryn Lewis.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1949-1952; 4 (Reel 20)
    58 pp.: Local union support for UMWA and United Steelworkers of America strikes and contract negotiations; mass meetings; United Steelworkers of America offer of gift to UMWA during 1950 UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA offer of strike fund assistance to United Steelworkers o f America during 1952 strikes; National Bank of Washington; UMWA district presidents; UMWA executive board members; Philip Murray; William Green; Benjamin F. Fairless; John Owens; Barnum L. Colton; Thomas Kennedy; William Hynes; John J. Mates; James W. Ridings; David Fowler; Ray Thomason; Tom Raney.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1949; 5 (Reel 20)
    11 pp.: Contract negotiations and strike settlement; comparison of pension plan with UAW and UMWA pension plans; Benjamin F. Fairless.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1950; 6 (Reel 20)
    16 pp.: Contract negotiations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); local union political activities; UMWA cooperation; local union support for UMWA contract negotiations; Justin McCarthy; Benjamin F. Fairless; Michael Honus.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1951; 7 (Reel 20)
    7 pp.: Southern organizing campaign; strikes; proposed 1952 special convention; John G. Ramsay; Philip Murray.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1952; 8 (Reel 20)
    145 pp.: Contract negotiations; strikes; Taft-Hartley Act; UMWA offer of strike fund assistance to United Steelworkers of America during 1952 strikes; National Bank of Washington; US Supreme Court decision regarding collective bargaining agreements; Taft-Hartley Act; political activities; UMWA executive board matters; radio broadcasts; public and local union support for UMWA offer of strike fund assistance; public relations; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); US government seizure of steel industry; 1952 special convention; Philip Murray; Thomas Kennedy; John Owens; James H. Terry; John J. Mates; Hugo L. Black; Justin McCarthy; Vincent Sweeney; Stanley H. Ruttenberg.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1953; 9 (Reel 20)
    6 pp.: Financial matters; UMWA-IBT-United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; newsclippings.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1954; 10 (Reel 20)
    141 pp.: Proceedings of the 1954 convention; UMWA cooperation; UMBWA-IBT- United Steelworkers of America unity negotiations; joint political activities; Allied Syndicates, Inc. (UMWA public relations firm); unemployment programs; economic analysis of industrial production; contract negotiations; criticism of UMWA presidency of John L. Lewis; Impact of automation on the steel industry; union organization; educational programs; legislative programs; safety and health programs; David J. McDonald; David B. Charnay; Dave Beck; John Herling; Gordon S. Brown; I.W. Abel; James G. Thimmes.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1955; 11 (Reel 20)
    19 pp.: Contract negotiations; economic analysis of industrial production; public relations activities; I.W. Abel; David J. McDonald.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1956; 12 (Reel 20)
    79 pp.: Contract negotiations and strike settlement; economic analysis of industrial production; labor-management relations; David J. McDonald; Kathryn Lewis; C.F. Hood.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1957; 13 (Reel 20)
    86 pp.: Statement before the US Senate Judiciary Committee Subcommittee on Antitrust and Monopoly regarding steel price increases; economic analysis of industrial production; contract negotiations; allegations of irregularities in union elections; adoption of code of ethics on use of union funds; proposed amendment of Taft-Hartley Act; state legislation; financial matters; A. D. Lewis; Robert Howe; Otis Brubaker; David J. McDonald; John Owens; I.W. Abel.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1958; 14 (Reel 20)
    24 pp.: Support for UMWA contract negotiations; UMWA cooperation; report on twenty years of progress (1938-1958) of the Kentucky state industrial union council, AFL-CIO; Labor's Non-Partisan League; public relations activities; David J. McDonald; Albert Whitehouse; Robert Howe; Welly K. Hopkins; Thomas Kennedy; Emory F. Bacon.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1959; 15 (Reel 20)
    108 pp.: Strikes and contract negotiations; WFTU; Taft-Hartley Act; use of injunctions in labor disputes; anti-Communist activities; publications; economic analysis of industrial production; foreign competition in steel industry; international labor relations; labor-management relations; Meyer Bernstein; David J. McDonald; R. Conrad Cooper; Dwight D. Eisenhower.
  - United Steelworkers of America., 1960-1962; 16 (Reel 20)
    15 pp.: Factionalism and internal politics; ascension of Thomas Kennedy to the UMWA presidency; contract negotiations; David J. McDonald; Thomas Kennedy; Emmett Thomas.